Hello English learners
welcome back to English
Pod, my name is Marco
and my name is Erica.
Today we're bringing you
another one of our sports
lessons and this time we're
going to go to a boxing match.
That's right so we're going
to be learning language
that you can use if you're
talking about boxing
but not only boxing
right? Right we can also use
this language for describing
a fight or somebody
that's fighting. Okay
so not that we're asking
our listeners to get
into fights but if ever you
see a fight at least now you'll
have the language to talk about it.
Exactly so let's
listen to a dialogue
for the first time. It might
sound familiar we have
the legendary Rocky
Balboa at English Pod fighting
for the heavyweight championships
so let's see what happens.
Coming to you live from
Las Vegas we're in the
beautiful MGM Grand
Hotel and Casino where the
world heavyweight championship
is about to get underway.
That's right Bob we're about to witness the
legendary Italian stallion himself Rocky
Balboa square off against
his lifetime rival Apollo Creed.
This will be a gross
match for sure both
fighters are in the ring
and we are about to begin.
In the blue corner
weighing in at 220 pounds
the former heavyweight
champion of the world
the master of disaster the
one and only Apollo Creed.
In the red corner
weighing 218 pounds
and with a record of 47
wins and 37 knockouts the
undefeated undisputed
heavyweight champion of
the world the Italian
stallion Rocky Balboa.
There's the bell and
this fight is underway.
Apollo quickly attacks
Rocky with quick strong jabs
Rocky dodge successfully
and counter attacks
with a strong right
hook. Apollo is cut Rocky
landed a strong blow to his
right eyebrow and cut him.
This is his chance Rocky quickly throws
a left right another left Apollo is getting
pounded Apollo recovers
with a powerful haymaker
and catches Rocky off guard he's down
the ref starts the count one two three one
Wow sounds like a great
fight. Amazing fight and
I don't know who's going
to win Rocky apparently
got knocked down what
do you think will happen.
Well if I know anything about Rocky Balboa
he will not stay knocked down the long.
All right so let's take a
look at some of the language
we saw in this dialogue
in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Well Rickfield said that we
have a very gruesome
match tonight.
A gruesome match. gruesome all
right so if something is gruesome
it's really it's bad it's
terrible it's bloody.
Okay bloody terrible
very hard or like gruesome
fight would be a
very bloody fight.
Yeah or a gruesome film.
Okay very good so gruesome.
Now they they mentioned
that both fighters are in the ring.
Both fighters are
in the ring. The ring.
Okay so the ring is the
physical space where they fight
but isn't it square?
Yeah it is square it does
not really circular but
it's called a boxing ring.
I'm not really sure why.
Well maybe one of our
listeners knows and can
tell us about that because
I am not an expert on
boxing but what I do know
is our next word. They
were describing Rocky
Balboa's career and they
said he had 37 knockouts.
Okay a knockout. A
knockout. In this sense
knockout is a noun. A
knockout is when the fighter
hits the other fighter
and he falls to the ground
and he can't get up in
10 seconds because he's
tired. He's dizzy. He's hurt.
Okay so that's a knockout.
Okay so this is a
technical boxing word it's
the action of falling to
the ground and not getting
up. Right but there's
also a verb to knock out.
Or to knock someone out. So exactly.
So when you say I knocked this guy out.
It means I hit him so
hard that he fell to the
floor and maybe he was
unconscious for a while.
So he fell asleep
basically. Almost.
Yeah so it's very similar the
noun form to the verb form like
basically if you knock
someone out you get a knockout.
Okay so two knocks
someone out. A knockout.
All right now for our next word we saw as
Apollo quickly began to jab Rocky Balboa.
So the noun a jab. So a jab. Quick jabs.
So a jab is a kind of punch right.
It's a fast short but
not very strong punch.
Okay so a technical
boxing word a jab. Hey jab.
This can also be a verb
right. Right so to jab.
Mm hmm to jab. Now
Apollo was throwing jabs
and Rocky began to
dodge. All right and that's
our next word to dodge.
Dodge. D-O-D-G-E to dodge.
All right so if you dodge
you're trying to avoid getting hit.
Right so you move your
body so that you're not hit.
Exactly. Now we can also
use it in different ways.
Not only do you
dodge when somebody
is trying to punch you. You can
also for example dodge a bullet.
Right so when you dodge a bullet you
avoid some bad situation or some bad event.
Right so we have many
examples of dodge used in other
contexts so why don't we
listen to some examples.
Example one. See that guy
dodging through the traffic.
He's gonna get hit by
a car if he's not careful.
Example two. Well
the storm turns south
so it looks like we
managed to dodge a bullet.
Example three. Look
you're the one who is in
charge of sales and
the numbers are down.
It's your problem so stop trying
to dodge your responsibilities.
You know that word reminds
me of another sport dodge ball.
Oh dodge ball exactly
the same principle.
Yeah but that's an
entirely different lesson.
I think we need to
focus here on the
boxing vocabulary. So
the announcers said that
Apollo is getting pounded
to get pounded. To get
pounded. Now if someone
is getting pounded they're
getting hit really hard
and a lot. So to get
pounded. And now we
have one more word and it's
also another boxing
term called a haymaker.
A powerful haymaker.
Okay so Apollo received a
powerful haymaker. Now
this word is actually new to me
so Marco what does it
mean? Basically it's a very
strong very wild punch.
Okay so you don't have
really good form your body is
kind of moving all over the place.
Right so you don't
have much balance
so you just throw your
entire body and your fist
at someone to hit
them as hard as you can.
That's a haymaker. All right
a technical boxing word here
for you guys but now we've got some
interesting phrases for you on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. All right so
on fluency builder today we're
going to take a look at
some of these phrases and
we have four of them
for you today so let's get
started with the first one.
Well the announcers said
that the boxing match
was about to get underway.
Okay to get underway.
So again this is another
way of saying about to
begin. Right. All right so
we're about to get underway
with this new project.
Or the meetings just about to get underway
so make sure everyone's here. Very good.
So the match was about to get
underway and the sports announcer
said that Rocky Balboa
is going to square off
against his lifetime rival.
So we're going to look
at this phrase to square
off against someone.
All right I'm going to
square off against Jim.
All right when you square
off against Jim you get
ready to fight with him
or to compete with him.
Right so we're about to have
a one-to-one competition.
So this is like a sports
word but it's also
really commonly used in
a lot of different contexts.
So why don't we hear
a few more examples
of how we can use
this phrase to square off.
Example one. The two
countries are moving their
armies close to the
borders as they prepare to
square off in a border
dispute. Example two.
Italy and Brazil are squaring off in the
final game this afternoon. Example three.
Least and Daniel squared
off against each other in
the marketing meeting today.
They were both pretty angry.
All right so great
examples and I think
we can use it now not
only in boxing but in other
situations. Now Bob said
that Rocky landed a strong
blow to land a strong blow.
All right so land a strong blow.
Now let's break this down.
So a blow. A blow is a punch
or a hit. Okay and when you
land a strong blow what
happens. You basically
successfully hit your
opponent with a punch or hit.
So you hit them so your
your fist meets their body.
Yeah so your fist
landed on their body.
So I could also
change this a little bit.
I could say I landed a punch.
Right or in boxing terms
he landed a strong left
jab. Okay so to land a blow.
The announcer described
it as rock through a
left to throw a left. So he
said he threw a left and right.
Now again we'll
take this one apart.
So a left. What are
we talking about?
Basically a left punch but we
can omit punch. Okay so it's a
punch with your left
hand but the verb throw.
You throw a left punch. So basically
you punch somebody with your left.
Okay so it's just
it's just another
way of saying to punch
someone. To punch someone right.
So Bob started to throw
some punches at the other guy.
All right or look over there.
That guy's throwing punches.
All right so to throw a left
to throw a punch. Now
again you can use this in a
lot of different ways
with a lot of different
types of punches. So you
could say to throw a jab.
Okay or throw an upper
cut or throw a hook.
Okay so now that we've seen
all these phrases why don't
we listen to the dialogue for the very last
time and we'll come back in a little bit.
Welcome back boxing
fans. My name is Rick
Fields and here with me
is the man with the Iron
Jaw Bob Copeland. Thank
you Rick. We're coming to
you live from Las Vegas.
We're in the beautiful
MGM Grand Hotel and
Casino where the World
Heavyweight Championship
is about to get underway.
That's right Bob. We're
about to witness the
legendary Italian stallion
himself Rocky Balboa.
Square off against his
lifetime rival Apollo Creed.
This will be a gruesome
match for sure.
Both fighters are in the ring
and we are about to begin.
In the blue corner,
weighing in at 220 pounds,
the former heavyweight
champion of the world,
the master of disaster, the
one and only Apollo Creed.
In the red corner,
weighing 218 pounds
and with a record of 47
wins and 37 knockouts,
the undefeated, undisputed
heavyweight champion of
the world, the Italian
stallion Rocky Balboa.
There's the bell and
his fight is underway.
Apollo quickly attacks
Rocky with quick strong jabs,
Rocky Johnson successfully
and Shadow attacks
with a strong right
hook. Apollo is cut.
Rocky landed a strong blow to
his right eyebrow and cut him.
This is his chance. Rocky quickly
throws a left, right and another left.
Apollo is getting pounded.
Apollo recovers with a powerful
haymaker and catches
Rocky off guard.
He's down, the ref starts to
count. One, two, three, one.
So as I mentioned,
Marco, I'm not really that
much of a fan or that
knowledgeable about boxing.
And actually, this is becoming a
theme and these sorts of lessons, isn't it?
Well, boxing is a very
popular sport in North America.
I'm not really that big of a fan, but I
have seen a couple of matches and it's very
interesting because as
we saw in our dialogue,
most big fights take place in
Las Vegas at some big hotel.
But you said it's super popular and
everyone wants to watch these matches and
obviously everyone
can't go to Las Vegas.
So what's the common way for most
people to watch these boxing matches?
Right. So in the United States, there's
something very popular called pay per
view and I'm sure in
your countries you have
something similar.
Basically pay per view, you
can buy the fight so you
can have access to it and
watch it on your TV. But
you only pay one time
to watch like maybe
two hours, right? Right.
So let's say you're at
your house, it's six o'clock
and the fight begins
at eight. So you can call
your TV cable company
or maybe use on the
internet with a credit
card and they activate it
on your TV so you can
watch the fight and when
it's over, well, you
finished watching it.
Now it's pretty
expensive, isn't it? Yeah.
Pay per view can be very
expensive depending on what
event it is because
sometimes it's boxing matches,
concerts, or special
events. So it can maybe
cost, I don't know,
$60, $80, maybe $100.
So it's very popular for one
house to buy the pay per view
and then many friends
come over and everyone
chips in with $5 or $10 and
everyone watches it on one TV.
All right, so the
pay per view boxing
party, a common way to
watch the sport in America.
Exactly. Now, why don't
you guys visit our website
and tell us about boxing.
Do you guys like it?
Do you know anything about it?
Are you guys maybe even
boxers yourself or former boxers?
All right, so we'll see
you guys at our website
and also if you have any questions or
comments, be sure to leave them there as well.
You can find us at
EnglishPod.com and until
next time, thanks for
listening and goodbye.